how we doing. Um, real quick before have
some questions about the players, I
think just on behalf of both of us, like
we just want to thank the respective
staff for the work that they put in, the
coaching staff, the scouting staff, the
football operations staff, people that
are involved in the process. I mean, we
wouldn't say it was seamless, but it's
pretty seamless. and just the knowledge,
the preparedness, the communication like
it's we operate and function as a unit
and that's how we built the program and
everything we do is about the team and
there's no better example of that than
the draft and the weekend and the
process we went through. So, you know,
on behalf of both of us, you know, we we
were able to do this without the staffs.
So, they're as big a part of this as
anybody and uh you know, they're a big
reason why we're you know, in the
position that we're in. So, you know, if
you guys want to just go ahead and just
start with some questions and then kind
of go through the day and and go from
there.
>> How good do you feel about being able to
get a player of McDonald's uh caliber in
the second round?
>> McDonald is a guy we all we all like
scouts, coaches, everybody, collective
group, everybody like the talent. Uh
young player, but he's he's grown. He
shows the strength, you know, in the run
game. He shows the ability to get off
blocks and finish. So very excited to
add a young defensive tackle to that
room and he only you know I know he'll
flourish with the guys that he'll be
learning from both sides of the
football. You always want to build in
the trenches and be strong in there line
of scrimmage with the first two picks.
How much do you feel like you'll have
really competitive practices when those
guys lock up and with your head to that
mix?
>> Yeah, we've added some really talented
guys that are competitors. They are
physical uh guys. So, we know it's going
to we've improved our team today and
that's what you want to do in the draft.
You want to improve your roster with a
ton of competitive guys and that's what
we did today. So, I'm excited to see
these guys get here uh get assimilated
to how we do things and see them go out
and compete. So, it'll be it'll be fun.
>> You often talk about guys that do it the
right way.
other things outside
of their physical building. Seems like a
little bit of interaction.
>> Yeah, they're they're all, as you guys
probably have noticed, they're all our
type of guys. They're they're football
first guys, high character guys, guys
who just love playing football, guys,
big smiles, big energy guys just, you
know, they're going to fit right into
our locker room, right? And not just the
person, but we feel like we got really
good football players as well. It always
starts with the film first and having
great character, great men on top of
that makes it even better. And we got
that in all the guys that we've chosen.
>> You uh mentioned that last night there
were guys that that you all wanted to
draft at 91 that you felt were going to
be discussed at 106. Were you able to
get those guys? Yeah, I mean really the
first two picks um of the day um in
FabetHei and Wood um you know with
Fabeti, you know, we kind of sat there
and picked at 106. We felt that was the
best thing. You started to actually see
a little bit of a run on the offensive
line there at the top of the round. Um
and then Woodazz was a player where we
kind of just moved back there a few
spots and we felt like just going back a
few grab a pick, we'd still be able to
get him at 123 or wherever we ended up
picking them. But I mean to do De Mo's
point talking about some of the earlier
players those were two players that we
had conviction like collectively
coaching staff kind of had a vision and
a role for them. Frank relative to
Woodaz also had a vision and a role. So
when you combine the two that's why we
talk through all these scenarios in all
these situations because we're trying to
fit play get the players here that fit
what we're doing and that the coaches
and the staff have a vision for the
player. We're never going to you know
square peg a round hole a player
regardless of what somebody might think.
In the end, we'll talk about it. If it
makes sense, then we'll try to make it
work. But obviously, those two players
were examples of players we were talking
about yesterday that happened to be
available today and we were able to add
them to the team today.
>> I saw the cameraman.
What did you like about
>> I'm pumping my fist on every The camera?
The camera just The camera only got that
one. Come on, Omar. We missed out on all
the good stuff. Good action. No, that's
the only one you saw. Well, that
reaction was for each and every pick. I
I love them all. No, no, for Beti. Uh,
but like to play a very smart player.
Uh, can play multiple positions. He play
guard, plays some center. So, having
that flexibility at at the interior of
our offensive line is uh you're excited
about him.
>> Nick, when you get a guy that had been a
ball like him, he talked about good line
about almost feel like you're feel like
you're starving, like you're that
hungry. What did you see from him just
in terms of mental makeup having had to
earn it all the way out of high school
now?
>> Yeah, really good. I mean, you know, not
necessarily transfer up, it kind of
transfer up. Kind of started at one
program and then elevated to another
program, but his mentality, his
leadership, just his overall presence. I
mean, he's a great kid. He's very smart.
Takes coaching. Um, and you kind of look
at his story and his journey, like he's
made himself into the player that he is.
And then our job is to make him a better
player relative to where he is right
now. So, um, great human being. Like we
had him in the building. Um, has some
leadership qualities, has some
toughness. I mean, he's sturdy as hell.
He's thick. He's really, really strong.
Um, so he's got the right makeup and the
right mindset, and he's just got a good
spirit about him.
>> Hey, Nick, you um I know this is just
the beginning, right? You just the draft
is the beginning, but all the work that
goes into it and being able to have your
or your kind of wish list getting and
having what you want. Can you talk about
what that feels like to be taking the
next step as you move forward?
>> Yeah, I mean we go into this you kind of
have I mean we both kind of have like a
list of players and then we kind of
match it up and say hey if we have the
opportunity to add these players to our
team then you know it'd be great for the
overall organization and what we're
trying to do and we were able to do that
here today but I mean this is one
snapshot so now we'll kind of pivot and
kind of take inventory. All right,
here's where we are today. probably some
things that'll happen here this
afternoon after the draft work through
on drafted for agency and then there's
still another grouping of players that's
out there that's available so we'll kind
of evaluate our team where are we can we
upgrade some spots even if we have a
player there currently maybe we replace
them with another option so I mean it's
pretty fluid here I mean this is I mean
obviously there's a lot of work and time
that goes into this from everybody um
but by the same token we're in the
offseason program we're kind of in phase
one we're going to eventually transition
to phase two where the players will
actually get on the field with the staff
and then we'll kind of keep track of
kind of what's going on leaguewide.
There'll probably be some attrition from
the draft players that were drafted
probably created spots or other
opportunities where players kind of get
knocked out and then we'll look to see
if there's somebody out there that makes
sense for us
by the time that you
get the scouting team. How much study do
you have to put into especially with the
amount of players that there is in the
draft also? at the same time getting
prepared for the next season.
>> Yeah, there is no offseason. It turn it
turns right into you know draft
preparation uh really starting at the
combine. So it was really really cool. I
think one of the first interviews I had
at the combine was was Marlin and that
that was a really cool moment for us to
be able to get him. Really like the tape
from my initial watch of him and to be
able to get him. So it's a it's an
ongoing process. I tell my my studying
never stops. Like I'm still watching
guys today trying to make sure you know
we're
correct on the guys that we're taking
and we all like the guys. So that
process never ends up until we have to
take the pick. So uh it's been a
thorough process, but my process is sped
up by the staff like our scouting
department. They lay so much groundwork
that I get a head start when I do begin
to watch guys. I know who to watch. I
know what areas to look for. So they do
an outstanding job of prepping me for
that.
>> And then you go in and you have draft
some players that come
at that position. How exciting is it for
you as a former player and as a coach
to, you know, get excited about getting
ready to watch that type of competition.
>> Yeah, football is all about competition.
Look, and that's what you add these
young guys to. We already have a really
good team and we had the opportunity,
you know, over the past couple days to
ask some really talented young men that
are going to come in and compete. Man,
competition only makes everyone better
and that's what we're going to see.
We're going to see our football team
improve once these guys get on the field
because they have to raise their level
of play to go and earn a spot and that's
what you that's what we're going to love
see. We're going to have some really
good battles in training camp and I
can't wait to watch them. Nick, when it
comes to Lewis Bond, what did you hear
from the Boston College staff from Bill
O'Brien just to kind of report you on
him?
>> Yeah, really smart, very instinctive,
good ball skills, um, kind of finds a
way to get open, very productive with
his opportunities. I know that was a
player that coach McDaniels spent time
with in the spring on the Zoom and he
said it was one of the smartest players
that he ever talked to as a part of this
process. So, and you see that in his
play, very dependable. He's in the right
spot. Um, good football player. I would
say he he has football player traits.
You might look at the card immeasurables
and say, "Well, he's a little, you know,
slower, a little shorter, but he
produced consecutively for multiple
years." So, obviously played in kind of
an NFL style offense and coach O'Brien's
system. So, some of the things will
carry over, some of the things will be a
little bit different, but you saw a lot
of good things on tape. And that was a
player like as we kind of worked through
today on Saturday, we were talking and
hey, what do you think? Yeah, we liked
it. We both liked the player. Ben liked
the player. So, all right, if we have an
opportunity to add him to the team,
let's figure it out. Which is why we
made the pick we did there in the sixth
round.
>> This is sort of like Christmas for y'all
that they you know they you got your
presents under the tree, you pull them
out, but now you start, you know, take
them out, start to play with them now.
When does, you know, you start to see
how the shine comes out, comes on like,
you know, how does it go move? Just talk
about moving from here.
>> Yeah. Moving forward. In uh next in two
weeks we'll have our rookie mini camp.
Most of the guys will be able to come in
and participate. We see the guys on the
field and that's the exciting time to
see guys actually out working with
coaches. You know, we get cuz coaches we
get really fired up about that first
watch that first opportunity to get the
guys in the Texans uniform to get them
on the grass. So, you know, we're
excited about it. You know, you've
watched the tape. We spent a lot of
time, you know, getting to know these
guys and our coaches have built already
built really great relationships with
these guys by zooming them 30 visits.
So, it's uh be more even more exciting
once we hit the grass and we can get
done with this
>> credit.
what kind
of balls?
>> And look, Kaden is a great football
player and for me, you know, we've had
success with smaller defensive linemen.
That doesn't necessarily mean that that
was what we were looking for all the
time. Like we just we had I've worked
with some really good coaches who were
able to get the best out of players and
the traits that they possess. those
smaller guys explosive traits they were
able to knock back and we've seen where
we you know you start to lose some in
the run game. So you get a guy like
Kaden who's not only just a big body but
he is an explosive guy. He has the
twist, he has the explosiveness and he's
stout versus the run. Like that's a a
bonafide defensive tackle that's going
to impact our defense in a in a major
way.
>> Thank You want to ask about the coal
underneath my tree that I open in my
presence?